[Genius Girlfriend]
[Episode 3]
"From the abrupt to the disordered..."
[Constantly Strive to Become Stronger;
Strive to Be Number One]
Duan Qiyan, seriously?
You're reading philosophy?
Do you even understand it?
Tang, can you just leave me alone?
I'm much better than you.
[Natural Philosophy]
I refuse to be looked down
upon by a fool like you.
This has nothing to do with grades.
It's mainly about one's aura.
And with your rough aura,
you're only fit to read something like
[Natural Philosophy]
immortal cultivation
or martial arts novels.
Me? Rough?
Hey, I've finished The Little Prince.
Here you go.
I was wrong.
You're not rough.
You're just too immature, little prince.
Let me tell you—
[The Little Prince]
the romance of The Little Prince
is something you will never understand.
Don't just laugh.
What kind of book did you put
in the reading corner?
I'd like to see.
Guys,
[Class Challenge Leaderboard]
who took Tang Tingting's book?
I have it.
Let me see.
[Constantly Strive to Become Stronger;
Strive to Be Number One]
The CEO's Private Sweetheart.
Typical Tang Tingting.
[Class Challenge Leaderboard]
This looks just like your kind of book—
shallow and a total waste of time.
What do you know?
Web romance is also
a type of modern literature.
Don't talk nonsense
if you don't understand.
Fine, then let me see for myself.
[The CEO's Private Sweetheart]
Let me read this out loud for you guys.
Mr. Dai shouted, "Come here and sit down!"
His voice startled Shen Meng.
Seeing that Shen Meng did not comply,
Mr. Dai pressed her step by step.
He whispered in her ear...
Give it to me!
"Why are you hiding?"
"The second button of my shirt...
-Stop reading!
-fits right into your fluttering eyelashes."
Give it to me!
What are you doing? Don't hit me.
Let's talk this out.
Don't hit me! Stop!
What are you doing?
Don't hit me!
Guys,
I finished reading
The Solitude of Prime Numbers.
[The Solitude of Prime Numbers]
But there's no name on it.
Whose is it?
Mine.
[Gödel, Escher, Bach: an Eternal Golden Braid]
How come you have this book?
When I went to get the book,
it was the last one left on the shelf.
Although it is a bit challenging to read,
I actually quite like its content.
I guess I was meant to read it.
[Reading Corner]
So you didn't leave after school that day.
What?
It's nothing.
I bombed the test today.
I got a math question wrong
in the fill-in-the-blank section,
and only scored 118.
But my parents said that
not getting a perfect score
means it's a total failure,
they even called me a loser.
But I really tried my best.
I'm so tired. I really want to escape.
But where can I go?
Jin Baihui.
I finished reading your book.
It was great.
I noticed some annotations inside—
I assume they're yours.
I really like them.
In 1915, Emmy Noether
developed Noether's theorem.
She has a famous quote:
"Mathematics is free
and unrestrained by the outside world."
What exactly are you trying to say?
I mean,
the essence of learning is exploration.
And exploration is fun.
I hope you can discover
the joy in it.
Don't put so much pressure on yourself.
[The Kite Runner]
You're just talking nonsense.
Did you come here just to pity me?
I didn't.
Who needs your pity anyway?
What do you know?
Do you really think a few comforting words
can solve my problems?
Stop acting so smart.
Lin Zhixia.
Don't be so smug.
I will surpass you. I definitely will!
Are you still upset about
what happened with Jin Baihui?
I'm reflecting on my experiences
and trying to learn from them.
I think I really need to work on my EQ.
Jiang Yubai,
let me know directly
if you find any issues with me,
and I'll correct them.
There's no need for that.
Why?
Just keep being yourself.
Once people get to know you better,
they'll all grow to like you.
Liar.
Since I was a kid, you're the only one
who has ever felt that way.
I really want to fix this.
Just tell me what the problem is.
Is it because I'm too blunt?
So it really is!
Your expression says I'm too blunt.
No.
Don't tell me I've said something
that accidentally hurt your feelings too?
When I was seven,
my mom took me to get an IQ test.
It was a free test
at the City Central Hospital.
My IQ was 174 back then.
The doctor said
the number would keep going up.
Jiang Yubai, what's your IQ?
Are you smarter than me?
No.
I wasn't that petty, was I?
Your expression clearly says
I did hurt your feelings.
Maybe,
occasionally.
But I actually don't remember much of it.
We are such good friends now.
Just say what's on your mind.
Don't make me guess.
For example,
the first semester of fourth grade...
You still remember something
from that long ago?
I remember you said,
"Only Jiang Yubai would listen
to me talk about physics and math,
even though he didn't understand a thing."
I guess I really was out of line.
And then there's your
"Human Observation Diary."
[Human Observation Diary
is a preliminary review of research]
[On the thinking patterns
of ordinary people.]
[By observing the author's deskmate,
Jiang Yubai,]
You want to study me
[And his cognitive limitations,
this paper further explores
[The thinking patterns of ordinary people]
just because
I'm an ordinary human?
Yeah.
And you even wrote in it,
"I found out that Jiang Yubai
knows nothing about
the famous General Relativity."
I thought you said you barely remembered?
How come you're reciting all this
like it was yesterday?
Fine, I'll keep that in mind from now on.
I feel like half of my competitive streak
was shaped by you.
I will admit my mistakes and correct them.
I'm apologizing to you right now.
Jiang Yubai is not an ordinary human—
he's a great genius.
No need.
I'll prove it with my own ability.
Okay, genius Jiang Yubai.
I shouldn't have told you this
in the first place.
Let's go.
Yes, King Jiang Yubai.
I'll just take another
two minutes of your recess.
At the end of this month,
the province-wide
Rising Star Math Competition
will be held in the city.
This competition
is a three-member team event.
So if you are interested,
you can form your own teams to sign up.
Please hand in your registration forms
to me before next Friday.
Okay?
Here.
Pass these on.
Class dismissed.
Jiang Yubai,
about that math competition just now,
do you want to team up with me?
Are you participating too?
Then the three of us can team up.
That makes a full team!
Jiang Yubai,
I was asking if you wanted
to team up with me.
The Three Departments
and Six Ministries system
was the core of
the central bureaucratic system
from the Sui and Tang
to the Song and the Yuan.
It marked the maturity of
the ancient Chinese bureaucratic system.
It divided
the central administrative organs
into three major systems:
decision-making, review, and execution.
Teaming up with Jiang Yubai means
the math competition is a piece of cake.
We're already
a sufficient condition for victory.
But before the competition,
I need to help him go over
the probability problems one more time.
He always gets stuck on Bayes' theorem.
I've made a pre-competition schedule.
If we follow this plan,
we can definitely get first place.
Lin Zhixia.
I can't team up with you.
Jiang Yubai.
Come here for a second.
Why won't you team up with me
for this competition?
Lin Zhixia.
As long as we team up,
there will be no suspense
in this competition.
Or rather, as long as you're in it,
there won't be much suspense
in this competition.
Because you've always been in first place.
To be honest,
you really are the most
capable person I've ever met.
Wouldn't it be nice
to win first place with me?
That would be nice.
It's just that
I don't want to rely on you to win.
More than that, I don't want to
just be the genius's teammate.
I also want to see how big
the gap between us really is
when we compete against each other.
All right then.
I accept your challenge.
Let's make a bet.
A bet?
Jiang Yubai,
if you get first place in our grade,
then I'll call you Mr. Jiang.
But if I get first place,
then you should call me
Ms. Lin to show your respect.
How about that?
Ms. Lin.
What? What did you just call me?
You want me to call you Ms. Lin again?
So you still remember, Jiang Yubai.
Of course I remember.
That's my childhood trauma.
Then I'm sorry to say,
you're going
to have "childhood trauma" again.
If you lose,
you have to buy me
strawberry milk for a month
as compensation for my emotional distress.
I lose,
and I still have to compensate you?
Of course.
Because of you,
I missed out on the chance
of participating in a competition
with a good friend.
Don't you think you owe me that much?
But what if I win?
You win?
I never thought about that scenario.
Just say what you want to say.
Do you know about
the province-wide
Rising Star Math Competition?
I know.
I signed up for it.
I need to pick two teammates.
They don't have to be from my class—
sophomores or seniors are all fine.
Can you join the competition with me?
My older brother is my student.
My older brother is my student!
Call me Teacher.
-Call her Teacher.
-Call me Teacher.
Sorry, I can't.
Zeqiu.
I'm sincerely inviting you.
Can you...
No, I can't.
You look ridiculous when you act cute.
I'm full. Figure it out yourself.
I'm really optimistic
about this Paul George card.
This card's value
is definitely going up in the future.
How about mine?
Cousins.
I went through a lot of trouble
to get it from my older brother.
If you ask me,
both of your cards are just mediocre.
I'm currently looking into
a limited-edition Kobe Gold Refractor.
Limited edition?
What are you dreaming about?
That's not something
us regular high school kids can have.
Don't be so quick to judge.
To be honest with you guys,
I'm about to get one.
Give it to me!
How are you going to get it?
Don't ask, just wait and see.
Let me see.
Be careful.
I'm fine.
Wan Chunlei.
I've signed up for
the Rising Star Math Competition.
Would you like to team up with me?
No, thanks.
I've already teamed up with someone else.
Hey, hear me out.
Because...
Duan Qiyan,
do you have a competition partner yet?
Do you want to team up with me?
Me? I think I'll pass.
I've been quite busy lately.
But your grades are really good, right?
It would be such a pity if you skip it.
Well, my grades are good for sure,
but my ambitions lie elsewhere.
Besides,
I might not be in last place,
but I'm definitely not
in first place either.
So I'll pass.
With me as your teammate, we'll be fine.
Lin Zhixia, can't you take a hint?
He has already rejected you several times.
He doesn't want to team up with you.
It's not like everyone
has to participate in that competition.
We're on our lunch break,
and you just keep going on and on.
You're so annoying!
Tang.
Don't you think you're
targeting her a bit too much?
The three of us were way louder
than Lin Zhixia just now.
Why are you only shouting at her?
Shut up!
You're annoying too.
Lin Zhixia.
Shen Fuxuan?
I came specifically to find you.
Find me?
That book of yours in the reading corner
at the start of the semester,
Gödel...
Gödel, Escher, Bach:
An Eternal Golden Braid.
Right.
That book is really hard to read.
I hope one day
I can fully digest it
and discuss it with you.
Of course.
About the math competition,
have you found any teammates yet?
Not yet.
Then,
can you count me in?
Are you willing to...
You're saying...
Of course!
But why are you willing
to team up with me?
Participating in the competition with you
should be quite interesting.
Actually, I've known about you
for quite a long time.
My mom mentioned you to me.
Your mom is...
Shen Zhaohua.
Professor Shen is your mom?
We've stayed in touch.
She often asks about my studies.
It's probably because
it's rare for her to meet someone
as talented as you.
I'm just interested
in the ocean and the starry sky,
and I read some books about them.
I bet you've had plenty of opportunities
to be exposed to interesting things
since you were little.
I...
I guess it's alright.
Then it's a deal.
We'll team up together.
Get one more teammate,
and our team will be complete.
I'll go find other students.
Kid,
regarding how to solve
the local micro-turbulence
in the aquarium,
do you have any ideas?
I think we can install
artificial coral reefs.
When micro-turbulence passes
through the reefs,
it breaks down into milder water currents,
reducing its destructive force.
Excuse me,
do you want to participate
in the math competition?
No, we don't.
We are not capable of that.
Sorry to bother you.
Excuse me,
does either of you want
to participate in the math competition?
No, we don't.
Jiang Yubai, we are preparing
for the competition.
Can you stop being distracted?
If Lin Zhixia can't find teammates,
she might not be able
to participate at all.
Isn't that better?
We have a better chance
of winning if she doesn't.
Winning would be meaningless
if she doesn't.
I mean,
if Lin Zhixia doesn't participate,
even if we win,
other students will think we win unfairly.
What's the point of a competition
if the highest score is removed?
This is a team competition.
If she can't even form a team,
she has already lost.
[Death Scythe]
Do you really like Han Geng?
It's rare for boys to like him.
[Of course, I have every album of his.]
[Hey, I don't know
what kind of person you are yet.]
I don't know
what kind of person you are yet.
Are you handsome in real life?
[Are you handsome in real life?]
[Well, not bad. A little handsome.]
[They all say I look like Han Geng.]
Really? Do you have any photos?
[I don't take photos. I'm introverted.]
It doesn't matter.
We've been chatting for so long.
[Well, it doesn't matter.
We've been chatting for so long.]
[And we're both his fans.]
And we're both his fans.
Do you want to meet offline
and make friends?
[Do you want to meet offline
and make friends?]
[Sure.]
Duan Qiyan, why are you here?
I'm going to the beach.
What are you doing here?
None of your business.
You dressed up today.
Look at this dress.
Are you on a date?
Yes.
I am on a date.
The friend I am meeting later
is very handsome.
He looks like Han Geng.
Just go. Don't get in the way here.
Looks like Han Geng?
Then do you think...
I look like Han Geng?
Angel's Tears.
Duan Qiyan, I...
What were you thinking?
Giving yourself such a cheesy name?
What does my name have to do with you?
You added me out of nowhere
and didn't even tell me.
It's none of your business if I add you.
Besides,
you accepted it, didn't you?
I...
Wait, stop it.
You have to think about it this way.
At least, I was the one who added you.
Think about it.
At the prime of your youth,
a young girl like you
meets someone offline.
What if you run into a bad guy?
Meeting a liar like you
-is worse than meeting a bad guy.
-Tang Tingting, let go!
No, I won't.
If you don't, I'll fight back.
Don't you dare!
Three, two, one.
You... let go, Tang Tingting.
You let go!
Tingting, are you two playing around?
Yeah, we are.
Take care, Auntie Liu.
Alright, have fun.
Take care.
Are you letting go or not?
You let go.
You... you...
let go.
You let go.
Tang Tingting, let go.
I won't. You let go first.
If you don't,
I'm going to suffocate.
Hurry up.
You let go first.
Be gentle.
Duan Qiyan.
Tang Tingting!
Uncle, he hit me!
Dad,
I didn't.
Auntie,
she started it.
What happened?
Tell me what happened.
I just got back
and saw you bullying a girl.
How do I usually teach you?
As a gentleman,
you must first...
Be responsible.
Then...
Know how to listen,
and not interrupt others casually.
And?
Respect women.
Did you do that?
No.
Tingting's mom, I'm really sorry.
I've failed to teach my son well.
Sorry for the trouble.
-Sorry. Sorry.
-Don't say that, Duan.
We both know our own kids best.
It takes two to tango.
Yes.
Don't hit the kid.
You even tackled him!
A girl tackled a boy?
Is that how a lady acts?
Exactly.
Unbelievable.
Auntie, you need to be the judge.
Today, I was online
and played a little joke on her.
And she tackled me.
Was that necessary?
It really wasn't.
Enough.
You think you're in the right?
Online?
Weren't you doing homework at home today?
When were you online?
Um, Tingting's mom.
If there's nothing else, we'll head back.
Alright, sorry for the trouble.
Please don't be so polite.
-I won't see you off.
-Bye. Bye.
Bye. Bye.
I...
I'll throw the trash out for you.
So gentlemanly.
See you. See you.
Thanks, Duan.
I'll settle the score with you
when we get home.
Here, throw it away.
[Points Card]
Dad.
Have some water.
Thanks.
My pleasure, Dad.
Tell me.
How many points
have you saved up on this card?
Not many.
It's fine.
I can check it even if you don't tell me.
I used to play too, right?
I've been there.
But the rule in our family
is leniency for confession
and severity for resistance.
You know this.
So I suggest
you just tell me.
I promise I won't hit you.
Really?
Of course.
Just tell me.
Fifty or sixty thousand.
Fifty or sixty thousand?
Dad, I'll never go again!
I mean it!
Dad!
Duan Wenming, be civilized!
It's illegal to beat kids!
Ouch!
Ouch, it hurts!
Class is over.
Let's go downstairs and play basketball.
Let's go.
I'm covered in bruises.
I think I'll skip it.
It's all because of that Tang Tingting.
She ruined my sports player card plan.
The limited-edition Kobe card
you mentioned last time?
Yes.
I bet
I found the only one in the whole city,
right at Lele Toys"R"Us.
That's their grand prize.
It takes 100,000 points to redeem it.
I worked hard to save up for over a week.
I finally managed...
to save half of the points, but...
my dad
snapped the points card in half.
Aren't you short of a teammate right now?
Duan Qiyan is now completely
obsessed with this.
You can start from this point
and get him on the team.
Arcade sports player card.
That's my blind spot.
I haven't really dealt with this before.
But we have a short holiday coming up.
Let's go check it out.
I've never even seen
these machines before.
Duan Qiyan tried for so long
and couldn't win the grand prize.
Can we do it?
Let's give it a try.
Duan Qiyan is just too obsessed.
I think there are some tricks
and patterns to these games.
Sir, your tickets are saved.
Okay, thank you.
What are you two doing here?
Duan Qiyan,
how about we make a deal?
What deal?
If we help you redeem
the sports player card,
you'll join Lin Zhixia's
math competition group.
What do you say?
Are you kidding me, Jiang?
The sports player card
has been there for so long.
Do you think you can easily redeem it?
Anyway, we are confident.
It just depends on whether you want it.
Fine.
If you can really
get me the card,
forget about teaming up,
I can even be your follower.
These are my remaining tokens.
You guys take them and play.
Everything here is a scam.
I've quit now.
Bye-bye. I'm leaving.
[Commemorative Kobe Card]
Why do I suddenly feel so competitive?
Me too.
[Commemorative Kobe Card]
Although it's my first time at an arcade,
it's even more fun than I imagined.
The music rising and falling
and the colorful lights
seemed to turn the whole world
into a giant candy box.
We tried all the games.
The sense of accomplishment
from completing challenges together
is more real and thrilling than any prize.
We even forgot
our original intention while playing,
which was to help Duan Qiyan
get the sports player card
to make him my teammate
for the math competition.
When the doll
we wanted most finally dropped,
I suddenly realized
my very first time at an arcade
was with Jiang Yubai.
It feels like whatever we do together,
we're blessed with incredible luck.
Perhaps,
having a good friend by your side
is the greatest reward
bestowed by fate.
Congratulations to both of you.
How...
did you...
do that?
Never mind that.
According to our previous agreement,
can you join my team now?
Are you really going
to join the competition?
Look, Lin Zhixia,
I don't really
like doing stressful things.
So let's just forget
about the competition.
Didn't we agree on this?
Don't you want the card?
Yes, I do want it.
But
let me think about the competition
a bit more.
Why are you breaking your promise?
I'm not breaking my promise, Jiang.
Zhixia is here.
-Hello, Mr. Duan.
-Long time no see.
This is my classmate, Jiang Yubai.
Hello, Mr. Duan.
Hello.
Have a seat.
Make yourselves at home.
You haven't visited in a long time.
What do you want for dinner?
I'll arrange it.
We don't need to stay for dinner.
I came to find Duan Qiyan
to talk about the math competition.
Math competition?
What math competition?
You didn't know?
I really didn't.
It's like this, Mr. Duan.
This is a very important
provincial math competition.
The best students
in the province are participating.
Because it's a team competition,
most of our classmates have formed teams.
But Duan Qiyan hasn't signed up yet.
So we wanted to try to convince him.
Just give it a try,
even if the chances are slim.
So you mean
this kid didn't even want
to participate in the math competition.
Is that what you mean?
No, Dad.
I've been planning it.
I just
don't know which team to join.
I take this competition very seriously.
I was planning to win a prize
to give you a surprise.
Isn't that perfect?
Lin Zhixia is the best in the school.
Isn't this the best opportunity?
That's right.
If you can team up with Zhixia,
isn't that a good thing?
What were you thinking about?
Sure.
Then I'll join.
We'll start making plans
when school starts.
Secure second
and aim for first in this competition.
Quite ambitious.
Secure second and aim for first.
Fine.
Anyway, I always
give clear rewards and punishments,
and I always keep my word.
Please help him out more.
Don't just chat. Have some fruit.
You guys keep talking.
I'm counting on you
to secure second and aim for first.
Great.
With Shen Fuxuan and Duan Qiyan,
my competition team is complete.
♪ Wandering light wind
drifts past your pupils ♪
♪ One second of encounter,
heartstrings stirred ♪
♪ The story feels altogether different ♪
What are you doing?
♪ How to describe
my whimsical wandering dream? ♪
♪ You softly answer my quirky side ♪
There was a leaf on your head.
♪ Such bliss to finally be understood ♪
♪ The moon drifts past the window ♪
What else can I do?
♪ How am I to understand? ♪
I mean,
how did a leaf get on my head?
♪ About you ♪
Why did it fall on my head?
♪ The moment our eyes met,
my world came alive with color ♪
♪ Could this be how love begins? ♪
♪ These unspoken feelings
are so hard to figure out ♪
There's a formula relating wind speed V,
the falling leaf's initial height H,
and wind direction θ.
♪ Hidden deep within your gaze ♪
♪ Sometimes, I imagine
drifting beyond the skies with you ♪
If even a falling leaf's trajectory
can be predicted by a formula,
♪ Shimmering light
dances over the flower in bloom ♪
then encounters between people
might also be a gentle algorithm
quietly run by the universe.
♪ After all we've been through,
our fates remain intertwined ♪
This is both scientific certainty
♪ Perhaps fate favors me now ♪
and emotional coincidence.
But eventually, all formulas
will collapse into one true equation.
♪ The moment our eyes met,
my world came alive with color ♪
♪ Could this be how love begins? ♪
♪ These unspoken feelings
are so hard to figure out ♪
♪ Hidden deep within your gaze ♪
♪ The moment our eyes met,
my world was filled with hope ♪
♪ Dim tender touches turn out to be love ♪
♪ Unsettling thoughts at last unfold ♪
♪ I return the moment you glance back ♪
♪ If reunion is fated ♪
♪ Wish upon that dust speck
amid flowing light ♪